A Guide to the Virginia Cooperative Extension Service Photographs, 1937-1966
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Virginia Cooperative Extension Service Photographs, 1937-1966
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 26/2b
This collection has been digitized and is available online.
4.5 Cubic Feet; 10 boxes
The Virginia Cooperative Extension Service Photographs, RG 26/2b, contains approximately 5,000 photographs of activities of the Agricultural Extension Service from 1937 thru 1966, primarily in the 1950s. Photographs depict 4-H activities, home demonstration work, food, breeding, field stations, gardening, poultry, dairy, and other subjects. The Extension Division, which was established in 1966, became the Virginia Cooperative Extension and Agricultural Experiment Station Division in 1995, often shortened to the Virginia Cooperative Extension (VCE).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Virginia Cooperative Extension Service Photographs were acquired by Special Collections prior to 2001.
Alternate Form Available
Images available online.
Historical Note
A University-wide Extension Division was established on July 1, 1966, by the General Assembly. Extension work at the university can trace its roots to 1906 when an extension program was established in Virginia. When the Smith-Lever Act of 1914 was passed, authority for extension, or demonstration, work was transferred to Virginia Tech and it became known as the Agricultural Extension. In 1995, the Extension Division became the Virginia Cooperative Extension and Agricultural Experiment Station Division, often shortened to the Virginia Cooperative Extension (VCE).
Scope and Content
The Virginia Cooperative Extension Service Photographs, RG 26/2b, contains approximately 5,000 photographs of activities of the Agricultural Extension Service from 1937 thru 1966, primarily in the 1950s. Photographs depict 4-H activities, home demonstration work, food, breeding, field stations, gardening, poultry, dairy, and other subjects. The collection contains photographs that were compiled into the book College of the Fields: Highlights of the Virginia Cooperative Extension Service (cataloged as LD5655.E62 1987).
Index Terms
Subjects:
Virginia Cooperative Extension Service; Home demonstration work -- Virginia; 4-H clubs; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Photographs; Virginia Cooperative Extension (1995-)
Contents List
This collection has been digitized and is available online.
- 4-H, 1945-1963 (Box 1)
- Achievement Day, 1949 (Box 1)
- 4-H Boys, 1949-1965 (Box 1)
- 4-H Girls, 1949-1957 (Box 1)
- Camps, 1950-1962 (Box 1)
- Conservation Camp, 1951 (Box 1)
- Holiday Lake, 1945-1958 (Box 2)
- Jamestown Camp, 1951-1960 (Box 2)
- Dairy, 1950-1953 (Box 2)
- 4-H Features, 1950-1952 (Box 2)
- 4-H Forestry, 1957 (Box 2)
- IFYE, 1952-1958 (Box 2)
- 4-H Fairs, n.d. (Box 2)
- Assorted Photographs, n.d. (18 folders) (Box 3)
- Landscaping, 1949 (Box 3)
- Livestock, 1945-1956 (Box 3)
- Lynchburg Farm Show, 1950 (Box 3)
- Poultry, 1950-1956 (Box 3)
- Orange Area Fat Pig Show, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
- Stuffolk Baby Beef Show and Sale, 1951 (Box 3)
- 4-H Electric Conference, n.d. (Box 3)
- 4-H Short Course, n.d. (Box 3)
- 4-H Electric Congress, 1951 (Box 4)
- 4-H Electric Congress, 1952 (Box 4)
- 4-H Short Course, 1949 (Box 4)
- 4-H Short Course, 1950 (Box 4)
- 4-H Short Course, 1951 (Box 4)
- Atlantic Rural Exposition, 1949 (Box 4)
- Atlantic Rural Exposition, 1950 (Box 4)
- Atlantic Rural Exposition, 1951 (Box 4)
- Atlantic Rural Exposition, 1952 (Box 4)
- Atlantic Rural Exposition, 1953 (Box 4)
- Atlantic Rural Exposition, 1956 (Box 4)
- Extension Conference, 1949 (Box 4)
- Extension Conference, 1952 (Box 4)
- Extension Conference, 1953 (Box 4)
- Extension Conference, 1955 (Box 4)
- Extension Conference, 1957 (Box 4)
- Features, 1950-1952 (Box 4)
- Instructional Pictures, 1949 (Box 5)
- Institute of Rural Affairs - County Group Photo, 1949-1950 (Box 5)
- Institute of Rural Affairs 1950, 1949-1953 (Box 5)
- Institute of Rural Affairs, 1954 (Box 5)
- Institute of Rural Affairs, 1955 (Box 5)
- Family Living, 1956 (Box 5)
- Labor Saving, 1949-1950 (Box 5)
- Exhibits, 1956 (Box 5)
- Negro Extension Work, n.d. (Box 5)
- Radio, 1950-1954 (Box 5)
- Reference Pictures, n.d. (Box 5)
- Technique, 1955 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous, 1949-1965 (Box 5)
- Landscape, 1949-1960 (Box 5)
- Clothing, 1945-1955 (Box 5)
- Community Improvement, 1950-1953 (Box 5)
- Food and Nutrition, 1944-1963 (Box 5)
- Home Economics, 1954-1956 (Box 5)
- Food Processing, 1949-1951 (Box 5)
- Home Demonstration, 1945-1956 (Box 5)
- Home Furnishings, 1945-1955 (Box 6)
- Home Improvement, 1950-1955 (Box 6)
- Home Management, 1946-1956 (Box 6)
- Housing, 1949-1956 (Box 6)
- Home Management - Miscellaneous, 1952-1960 (Box 6)
- Outdoor Cooking, 1954-1963 (Box 6)
- Rural Arts, 1949-1950 (Box 6)
- Soil Conservation, 1944-1959 (Box 6)
- Agriculture Economics, 1945 (Box 6)
- Agriculture Engineering, 1946-1954 (Box 6)
- Buildings, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
- Machinery, 1953 (Box 6)
- Agronomy, 1938-1959 (Box 6)
- Corn, 1949-1959 (Box 7)
- Grass Silage, 1951-1954 (Box 7)
- Hay, 1944-1958 (Box 7)
- Peanuts, 1944-1957 (Box 7)
- Small Grains, 1945-1955 (Box 7)
- Sorghum, 1944-1955 (Box 7)
- Soybeans, 1951 (Box 7)
- Tobacco, 1949-1960 (Box 7)
- Agriculture Science, n.d. (Box 7)
- Horses, 1945-1958 (Box 7)
- Swine, 1945-1953 (Box 7)
- Equipment, 1952 (Box 7)
- Housing, 1952 (Box 7)
- Pasture, 1945-1958 (Box 7)
- Handling Swine, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
- Dwarf Cattle, 1953-1957 (Box 7)
- Beef Cattle, 1953 (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous (Beef/Cattle), 1945-1963 (Box 7)
- Feed - Cattle, 1947-1957 (Box 7)
- Cross Breeding, 1949-1953 (Box 7)
- Irrigation, 1949-1955 (Box 7)
- Equipment, 1951-1956 (Box 8)
- Cows and Calves, 1952-1953 (Box 8)
- Water, 1950-1955 (Box 8)
- Pasture - Cattle, 1944-1959 (Box 8)
- Sales, 1945-1957 (Box 8)
- Dublin Feeder Calf Sale, n.d. (Box 8)
- Pasture - Sheep, 1944-1956 (Box 8)
- Feed - Sheep, 1946-1959 (Box 8)
- Lamb Care, 1950-1953 (Box 8)
- Breeding Flock, 1944-1953 (Box 8)
- Sheep Equipment, 1950-1956 (Box 8)
- Sheep Handling, 1956 (Box 8)
- Eastern Stud Ram Sale, 1950 (Box 8)
- Shearing and Wool Preparation, 1946-1957 (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous - Sheep, 1951-1959 (Box 8)
- Parasite, 1946-1950 (Box 8)
- Sale Sheep, 1945-1955 (Box 8)
- Fitting, 1946-1956 (Box 8)
- Poultry, 1945-1960 (Box 8)
- Turkey, Geese, and Ducks, 1937-1960 (Box 9)
- Dairy, 1946-1963 (Box 9)
- Bulls, 1950-1955 (Box 9)
- Cows, 1946-1960 (Box 9)
- Dairy - Miscellaneous, 1945-1964 (Box 9)
- Lab, 1947-1962 (Box 9)
- Pasture - Dairy, 1946-1955 (Box 9)
- Interior, 1945-1964 (Box 9)
- Exterior, 1945-1954 (Box 9)
- Entomology, 1944-1958 (Box 9)
- Farm Labor, 1945-1947 (Box 9)
- Farm Tour, 1946-1956 (Box 9)
- Field Station VPI, 1949-1957 (Box 10)
- Field Station Glade Spring, 1955-1959 (Box 10)
- Field Station Holland, 1950-1959 (Box 10)
- Field Station Middlesburg, 1950 (Box 10)
- Field Station Orange, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
- Field Station Steeles Tavern [McCormick Farm], 1956-1959 (Box 10)
- Field Station Williamsburg, 1950 (Box 10)
- Field Station Winchester, 1959 (Box 10)
- Field Station Charlotte, n.d. (Box 10)
- Field Station Chatham, 1949 (Box 10)
- Field Station Front Royal, 1949-1951 (Box 10)
- Forestry, 1945-1960 (Box 10)
- Vegetable Gardening, 1945-1956 (Box 10)
- Landscape Gardening, 1946-1960 (Box 10)
- Ornamental, 1945-1965 (Box 10)
- Horticulture, 1944-1966 (Box 10)
- Pomology, 1944-1951 (Box 10)
- Pruning, 1947-1957 (Box 10)
- Small Fruits, 1947-1949 (Box 10)
- Staff, 1945-1956 (Box 10)